Mobile Suit
Rage on! Rage on! Rage on! Gundam!
Moeagare! Moeagare! Moeagare GANDAMU!
You must run forth!
Kimi yo hashire
If you are still burning with furious rage...
Mada ikari ni moeru toshi ga aru nara...
You must fight the towering foe!
Kyodai na teki o
Fight! Fight! Fight!
Uteyo! Uteyo! Uteyo!
Bring to bear the rage of justice, Gundam
Seigi no ikari o butsukero GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
Rise once more! Rise once more!
Yomigaeru! Yomigaeru!
Rise once more! Gundam!
Yomigaeru GANDAMU!
You must seize the power!
Kimi yo tsukame
Fly toward the galaxy, Gundam!
Ginga e mukatte tobeyo GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
Just before Operation Odessa...
...the White Base was critically damaged
in combat, and made a crash landing.
Although the Zeon attack force
had withdrawn for the time being...
...there was no telling
when they would attack again.
Matilda's Rescue
The one on the right should be it.
It's no good.
Can't we use the cord for the engine No. 2?
I think the scale is different.
Hurry up, guys.
I'm running out of paper.
Mr. Kai! Someone's going to call you
a coward again.
Let's see what the pressure is here...
Can we manage with what we have?
I don't think so.
We've tried everything, but it's no go.
I see. If the enemy attacked now, we'd be...
We are getting supplies, right?
Yes. We made a request to General Revil.
Ms. Mirai, Mr. Bright is calling for you.
What is it, Bright?
I'd like you to be my substitute.
Take over for me?
A ship without a commander
seems pathetic. But... I can't do it.
None of us can.
I'm filled with shame when I think
that my fear may be what's making me ill.
You mustn't...
Here are the basics of ship command.
If you study this...
But... that's not enough.
I know you can do it.
Bright...!
You'll do it, won't you?
I'll be better soon.
Right. I'll try my best.
Meanwhile, having received
the White Base's resupply request...
...General Revil of the Federation Forces
had arrived at the European frontline base.
This was so that Operation Odessa could
happen before Rear Admiral Kycilia...
...sent reinforcements to M'Quve's base.
However, prior to this offensive...
Even if the attack is coming from
just one ship...
...if M'Quve is attacked from behind,
he'll panic and make his move.
But I understand they're badly damaged
after M'Quve's attack.
This plan might work because
they assume that, General Elran.
Matilda...
The rest depends on whether your squadron...
...can repair the White Base's engines.
Yes, General Revil.
No matter how bad the damage.
In addition, there's another item
I want you to deliver to the White Base.
Though they'll probably resent
being the guinea pigs again.
I want them to do the testing
for the Gundam's power-up mecha.
Gundam's...?!
Here's the documentation.
Thank you.
General Revil.
Why are you giving so much support
to a unit that hasn't been properly organized?
We can't use the regular military
for experiments.
This is also the decision of General HQ.
Thank you for informing me.
But you don't know any details
about the Gundam's power-up?
Unfortunately, General Elran didn't have
a chance to check before the White Base...
I understand.
Tell Elran that he should restrain himself
in the Odessa offensive.
Yes, sir!
So, the Federation is getting impatient.
In this battle, the first to move will lose.
Clink. Take 3 Goufs with 3 Dodai YSs...
...and hit the Medea transport team.
Yes, sir!
Take escort fighters as well.
Mirai.
What is it?
A coded message from
General Revil just came in.
I've deciphered it with the computer.
I'll display it.
Go ahead.
This is Revil. My apologies
for taking so long to contact you.
Lieutenant Matilda is delivering
your supplies.
You must join Operation Odessa
as soon as repairs are complete.
Yes, sir!
I've also sent along
new parts for the Gundam.
I'm sure they will be quite useful in battle.
I hope the pilots will fight better with them.
That's it? We don't even know
when Operation Odessa begins.
I'm sure Ms. Matilda...
...I mean, Lieutenant Matilda...
will give us the details.
I'm sure.
I wonder what the new Gundam parts are?
I hope it's something that'll make it easier
for Amuro and the others.
Detecting a formation at 11 o'clock.
Just when we're almost there.
Zeon?
Yes.
It's strange...
There can't be that many people
aware of our movements.
All units, prepare for anti-air combat!
Maintain current combat formation!
Send General Revil an SOS, just in case.
Yes, ma'am!
I've got you!
Transports weighed down by their cargo
are a piece of cake!
Receiving an SOS from
the Medea transport squadron!
The Medea?! What's the distance?
180 km, northwest!
What to do...
Without those supplies...
the White Base can't move.
We need the Medea to come to us.
Sayla. We need to assist
the Medea transport squadron.
Roger!
Amuro! Kai! Hayato!
Please launch!
We're rescuing Matilda's squadron.
Ms. Matilda's in trouble...?!
No! Wait, Sayla! Stop the launch!
Why?
Well... Without the Core Fighters...
...the immobile White Base
will be defenseless.
If the enemy hits us then...
Amuro, go to the Core Fighter!
Job John and Hayato, to the Gunperry!
Load the Gundam parts!
Kai, to the Guncannon!
If that made you angry, you can punish me.
Sayla!
Bright left me in charge...!
Never mind.
Here I go!
Do your best, Kai.
Matilda's transport squadron
is bringing us emergency supplies.
Yeah, yeah. Sayla, you always flatter us.
Here I go, then!
Gunperry, heading out!
We'll just have to pray that
the enemy doesn't come here.
Mirai. Why don't you
go sit in the captain's seat.
It's more relaxing here.
Maybe we should have everyone
on anti-aircraft watch.
Yes... You're right.
Ms. Matilda.
Please hang on until I get there.
Lieutenant Matilda! No. 5's been hit...
No matter! Fly lower to the ground!
Yes, ma'am!
You're not touching Ms. Matilda,
or the supplies!
It's a Core Fighter!
Very fast, indeed.
But is it a match for those
Zeon mobile suits, the Goufs...
The Dopps are no problem.
But where are the Goufs?!
Damn!
You're not getting me now!
Down! Down! Down!
That's one Gouf...! Next...?!
I've got to get between the enemy
and the Medea, or I'll hit Ms. Matilda!
Hurry up, Mr. Kai!
I'm running out of ammo!
Mobile Suit
Gundam
M-Mirai.
You can't just wait.
Do repairs...
Repairs!
You have to do what you can
while there's time.
This is no time to be reading that.
Everyone...
It's true, Ryu...
The way you did it wasn't the smartest.
But you taught us all by your example.
A person's value depends
on what that person does.
You were strong...
...that's why I want to be like you...
Ryu...!
Mirai...!
Make your own decisions...
...and take action.
Amuro, can you hear me?!
Amuro, I'm entering the docking area!
Can you make it here?!
I read you, Hayato!
Enemy aircraft at 5 o'clock!
We don't have data on it!
Don't be stupid. We've got
all the data on the Trojan Horse.
I see it now! A splitting type!
A splitting type?!
That's the one that carries
the Gundam mobile suit!
Habe, cease attack on the Medeas!
We're going after the splitting type!
Splitting type? What's that?!
Is the mobile suit in it?
That's right. Have the remaining Dopps
chase the fighters away!
Amuro! You're going to transfer
to the Gundam right here?!
We have to! The Core Fighter
isn't enough to defeat the Goufs!
All right! Activating laser searcher!
Roger!
Laser searcher activated!
Synchronizing!
A Gouf!
Now! Get the fighter!
This guy here's a bit slow, y'know.
Hey! Hurry up and do the Gundam thing!
Thanks! Give me cover!
There are Goufs around the Medea, too!
I see that!
Docking searcher... activated!
10... 9...!
All right, Hayato!
6... 5...
Releasing B Parts!
All right! Searcher synchronized!
Releasing A Parts!
Converting to a mobile suit, huh?!
Damn Gouf! You'll pay for that!
Oh, no!
I hope that's not Ms. Matilda's!
No. 1! No. 4 is down!
Please go on ahead!
No. 4 has the Gundam's power-up mecha.
We're going to land the formation.
But our two aircraft can still get away!
We can't abandon the Gundam's
power-up mecha.
They landed?!
This is bad!
Damn! Is it that Gouf again?!
You!
Hurry up! Get the G-Mecha unloaded!
We're going to blow!
Keep up the anti-air fire!
There's one enemy mobile suit left!
Amuro! What are you doing?!
Ms. Matilda's going to be hit
unless you get here quickly!
Of course, I should probably
try to shoot it down...
Power up the G-Fighter's engines.
We'll have the Gundam use it!
You think he'll learn to use it that quickly?
Amuro can do it.
Sayla...?
What does a commander do at time like this?
Sorry. Never mind.
Ms. Mirai, at times like this, we feel safe
when a commander looks calm and confident.
Oh...?
Ah, you're right...
No enemies closing in, are there?
No sign of any. The Medea transports
seem to be stalled as well.
Uh, Sayla, can you inform
the mechanics?
Cancel level 1 battle stations
and resume repairs.
Is that safe?
Yes, the enemy doesn't have
much fighting strength.
That's why it's taking them so long.
It'll be fine. They won't come here.
Damn Gouf! Seems to be
getting stronger and stronger!
Can I do it?!
Is he finished?!
Go!
He got me! My engine...!
Oh, no! My leg circuits are all shot!
I've got to get to Ms. Matilda, quickly!
Another one?!
Mirai, has Matilda's squadron arrived?
You're awake?
Everything's fine.
They say they should be here in 5 minutes.
I see. They got through
the Zeon siege, huh?
I guess that's why they made her
a First Lieutenant.
Sorry... I'd like to rest some more.
Sure.
It's no good...!
I can't move freely!
What to do?!
At this rate, I'll be over-powered!
Is this it...?!
No, you're not going to get me!
Again?!
Amuro!
It's the power-up mecha
Ms. Matilda brought!
We can put the Gundam on it!
All right...! Let's try it!
Here we go, Amuro!
It's coming!
You lost too much power already!
I'm taking you down!
Bastard!
Hayato! Ram him!
Hayato! Turn! Hurry!
Incoming!
The G-Fighter...
So that's...
Well done, Amuro.
And Hayato.
I got the report.
Ms. Mirai. As acting commander,
you protected the Medea squadron well.
Thank you.
I'd like you now to
contact the Medea squadron...
...and expedite repairs to the White Base.
Yes. Thank you very much.
I feel more and more ashamed of myself.
You shouldn't, Mirai.
You held on well.
And you were able
to put Bright at ease, too.
Thank you, Sayla.
It means a lot to me,
coming from you.
With all this, the White Base
will be fixed up in no time!
Of course!
That's the second time
I've been saved by you...
...Amuro and Hayato.
And Kai too. Today must have
been the toughest on you.
Well... That was nothing, really...
Practically a piece of cake.
You're so dependable, Kai.
Well...
Now, let's have you take a look
at all the new Gundam power-up parts.
Yes, ma'am!
You know, I'm going to try even harder
and get even better...
Huh?
Hey! Wait for me!
Matilda dies protecting
the White Base...
...along with many of her brave comrades.
The Dom heavy mobile suits,
nicknamed the Black Tri-Stars...
...make for an unrelenting
show of ferocity.
Mobile Suit Gundam. Next episode...
Black Tri-Star.
Next Time
Black Tri-Star
Will you be able to survive?
Amuro, do not look back
The star shining far off in space...
Amuro, it's your homeland where you were born
Do you remember the days of your childhood?
The morning when you woke up in warmth?
Amuro, do not look back, Amuro...
A man must hide his tears, hide his tears
Only look to tomorrow, to tomorrow forever...